## Anantha Raju C

Software Engineer

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/anantharajuc https://anantharajuc.github.io/

https://github.com/AnanthaRajuC 🖹 https://stackoverflow.com/users/3711562/anantha-raju-c

#### **Profile**

**Java** (**Spring Boot**) developer with **6+ years** of professional experience working on **back-end systems** in an enterprise (**B2B2C**) environment building **Web Applications** for products in Customer Engagement domain (**Mar-Tech/Ad-Tech**).

Proficient in integration of **RESTful Web Services** right from requirement specifications, planning, designing, implementation, configuration, testing & documentation till closure based on Agile Methodologies.

## **Key Skills**

Web Application (Backend) Design & Development, Project Management, Agile SDLC.

#### **Technical Skills**

**Spring Boot** (Spring Data JPA, Spring Data MongoDB, Spring Web, Spring Security, H2 Database, Java Mail Sender, Lombok, Thymeleaf, Flyway Migration)

**AWS** (RDS, Elastic Beanstalk, DynamoDB, IAM) • **Git** (GitFlow Workflow, Feature Branch Workflow)

**RESTful Web Services** (HATEOAS) • **Testing** (JUnit, AssertJ, Mockito) • **NoSQL** (MongoDB) • **MySQL** 

GitHub • Object Oriented Programming • Data Structures • Java • Maven • Docker

Linux • Swagger UI • HTML

### **Certificates**

(Qwiklabs)

Google Cloud Platform and Amazon Web Services ☑

IBM Marketing Cloud ☑

Adobe Marketing Cloud 🛮

## **Key Result Areas Across Projects**

- Provided overall leadership to the entire team including managing deliverables of other functional team leaders.
- Analyzed & designed architecture definition, design patterns and solutions for the project; designed & selected appropriate technologies for development approach.
- Monitored development activities and conducted timely risk assessment & mitigation; managed and provided technical & process level guidance/support to the project team.
- Prioritized project initiation and reporting w.r.t. development projects to senior management and stakeholders.
- Gathered requirements from the client, prepared estimates & requirement specification, created prototypes and developed technical specification documents along with team members.

## **Professional Experience - Summary**

#### **Software Engineer,** *Customer Centria* □

10/2015 - present | Bangalore, India

- Responsible for integrating Customer Centria's flagship Marketing Campaign Product Suite **CC Engage** with several communication channels of other enterprise grade Mar-Tech solutions.
- Responsible for developing **Proof-of-Concept** Product and Solution Implementation for prospects as per their business use-cases during **Pre-sales** & **Implementation** cycle.
- Significant experience in working with customers, project managers and technical teams for securing & executing concurrent projects.
- Conducted multiple Online/Off-line Training Sessions on the Mar-Tech Industry and the in-house Marketing Automation and Data Management Platform product based on previous client use cases to several recruits.

## **Product - CC Engage**

## **Omnichannel Marketing Automation Platform**

2016 - present | Bangalore, India

CC Engage is an Enterprise Grade Digital Marketing Product Suite.

- Integrated Core features of (Silverpop/IBM Watson Campaign 2 /acoustic 2) with CC Engage via RESTful web services.
- Involved in development & maintenance of product features along with custom feature development for clients during the implementation cycle.
- Integrated multiple communications channels (SMS, Email, IVR, Social) from multiple vendors via REST Web Services Facebook Messenger ☑, Whatsapp Business Solution ☑, mapp/Teradata ☑, Ozonetel ☑, Karix ☑, Alot Solutions ☑, Twilio ☑, SendGrid ☑.
- Responsible for developing the back-end service for Mobile Push Notification (**Android**) as a communication channel via **Goolge Cloud Messenger** (GCM). Migrated the aforementioned Mobile Push Notification service from GCM to **Firebase Cloud Messaging** (FCM).

## **Project - Deltin (Delta Corp Limited)**

### **CC Engage Platform,** (Data & Campaign Management)

2017 - present | India

Deltin is a listed company in gaming and hospitality industry.

- Accountable for the off-site deployment (**On-premise**) and eventual migration to **Cloud** (AWS) of Omnichannel Marketing Automation tool with multiple data sources.
- Responsible for overall project from gathering the requirements to implementing the use cases, RESTful
  Web Service Integration with Multiple Email (Juxtmail, MAPP/Teradata) and SMS (Ozonetel) Gateway
  vendors.
- Designed an algorithm and developed the code to automate the Batch Processing of Email & SMS marketing campaign's as per business requirement.
- Completed **Documentation**, **Bug Fixes** and **Test Cases** on the features developed.

## **Pre-Sales Engineering**

## **CC Engage Platform,** (Data & Campaign Management)

10/2015 - present

- Pre-Sales Experience of Enterprise Data Management & Marketing Automation Solution across industry verticals such as **BFSI**, **Retail**, **Telecom**, **Airlines**.
- Study the prospect, find the product fit by identifying relevant use-cases and finally design, develop the same using CC Engage
- Lead a team for the development of Prospects' Business Use Cases into solution implementation during the Proof-of-Concept development

### **Open Source**

## **Spring Boot Application Template,**

08/2018 - present

55 Stars, 180 Forks on GitHub □

This repository contains a recipe/scaffolding for bootstrapping a Web Application with the features & Technology stack listed below. Delete the sample code (or keep it.) and add your own, you're good to go.

Essentially it's a simple **on-demand application back-end** for rapid-prototyping.

Solely engineered and maintaining the application.

Features: Internationalization, API Rate Limiting, RBAC with JWT, JPA Auditing, HTTPS, Continuous Integration

**Tech Stack**: Spring Boot, Spring Security, Swagger UI, Bootstrap, Thymeleaf, Git, GitHub, MySQL, Docker, dockerhub, Travis CI

#### Blog

## https://anantharajuc.github.io/

2015 - present

A Personal blog on Technology where i capture my experience with new tools, platforms and services.

All posts follow a minimalist tutorial-style format with images wherever necessary to document a concept/process for myself and acts as a source of quick reference.

This site is a fork of an existing Jekyll theme and over the years I've personally redesigned it to meet my requirements.

#### **Publications**

## **Resource Management by Virtual Machine Migration** in Cloud Computing, International Journal of Computer

12/2015

Science and Mobile Computing 🛮

- Features include improvement of Power utilization in a Simulated Data center, over existing systems.
- Developed using Java and CloudSim simulation Framework.

#### **Education**

# Masters of Technology (M. Tech), Computer Science Engineering,

Bangalore, India

Visvesvaraya Technological University (VTU) □

# Bachelor of Engineering (BE), Computer Science Engineering,

Bangalore, India

Visvesvaraya Technological University (VTU) □